Yikun Ban

yikunb2@illinois.edu +1-3123426323 www.banyikun.com

Research Interests

My research interest is in provable online-learning algorithms to tackle the exploitation-exploration dilemma in sequential decision making, and core research areas lie in multi-armed bandit/reinforcement learning overlapped with deep learning theory, meta learning, active learning, and transfer learning, with applications in recommender system, online advertising, and computer vision.

EDUCATION

University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaig, Illinois, USA Ph.D. in Computer Science. Advisor: Prof. Jingrui He.	Aug., 2019 - Present
Peking University, Beijing, China M.S. in Computer Science.	Sep., 2016 - Jun., 2019
Wuhan University, Wuhan, China B.S. in Spatial-information & Digitalized Technology	Sep., 2012 - Jun., 2016
RESEARCH EXPERIENCE	

Topic: Machine Learning and Data Mining, UIUC

Aug., 2019 - Present

Work with Prof. Jingrui He, Prof. Arindam banerjee, and Prof. Hanghang Tong.

- Linear Contextual Bandits, Neural Contextual Bandits.
- Meta Learning, Active Learning, Transfer Learning
- Regret Analysis, Convergence and Generalization of Deep Neural Networks.

Topic: Graph Mining, Tsinghua University

Jan., 2018 - Jan., 2019

Work wth Prof. Wei Xu, Dr. Ling Huang, and Dr. Yitao Duan.

• Anomaly Detection, Clustering, Complexity Analysis.

Publications

- Yunzhe Qi, **Yikun Ban**, and Jingrui He. "Neural Bandit with Arm Group Graph". 28th ACM SIGKDD Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining (**KDD'22**)
- Yikun Ban, Yuchen Yan, Arindam Banerjee, and Jingrui He. "EE-Net: Exploitation-Exploration Neural Networks in Contextual Bandits". 10th International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR'22, Spotlight).
- Yikun Ban, Jingrui He, and Curtiss B. Cook. "Multi-Facet Contextual Bandits: A Neural Network Perspective" . 27th ACM SIGKDD Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining (KDD'21)
- Yikun Ban, Jingrui He. "Local Clustering in Contextual Multi-Armed Bandits". The Web Conference 2021 (WWW'21).
- Yuchen Yan, Lihui Liu, **Yikun Ban**, Bayou Jing, and Hanghang Tong. "Dynamic Knowledge Graph Alignment". 35th AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (**AAAI'21**).
- Yikun Ban, Jingrui He. "Generic Outlier Detection in Multi-Armed Bandit". 26th ACM SIGKDD Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining (KDD'20).
- Yikun Ban, Xin Liu, Ling Huang, Yitao Duan, Xue Liu, and Wei Xu. "No Place to Hide: Catching Fraudulent Entities in Tensors". The Web Conference 2021 (WWW'19).

Preprint

- Yikun Ban, Yunzhe Qi, Tianxin Wei, and Jingrui He. "Neural Collaborative Filtering Bandits via Meta Learning". ArXiv:2201.13395.
- Yikun Ban and Jingrui He. "Convolutional Neural Bandit for Visual-aware Recommendation". ArXiv:2107.07438.

SELECTED HONERS

- Student Travel Awards (KDD'20 and KDD'21)
- Outstanding Students of Peking University, 2017-2018.

- Outstanding Graduate Student of Wuhan University, 2012-2016.
- Excellent Students Scholarship of Wuhan University, 2013-2015.
- Outstanding Students of Wuhan University, 2012-2016.

SELECTED AWARDS

- First Prize, The "China Software Cup" Software Design Competition for College Students (Top 0.1 %, 2859 teams involved), Aug., 2015
- Second Prize in National Finals, First Prize in Provincial Finals, The "Challenge Cup" China College Student's Entrepreneurship Competition (Top 0.2 %, 5000+ teams involved), Nov., 2014

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

CS412 Introduction to Data Mining (2021 Fall)

Aug., 2021 - Dec., 2021

Teaching Assistant. Instructor: Prof. Arindam Banerjee

MENTOR EXPERIENCE

- Yunzhe Qi, PHD student in iSchool at UIUC. Research Topic: Contextual Bandits.
- Yuheng Zhang, PHD student in CS at UIUC. Research Topic: Neural Active Learning.

ACADEMIC SERVICE

• Program Committee in NeurIPS'22, ICML'22, KDD'22, AAAI'22, SDM'22, KDD'21, IJCAI'21, CIKM'21.

SKILLS

• Python, C/C++, Java, Scala, Swift, Matlab.